U.S. Emergency Board No. 111 Records 5042
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board No. 111 Records
1952-1955
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board
5042
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Transcripts and exhibits, Emergency Board no. 111, 1955. Wage-rules case. International Brotherhood of Teamsters and Brotherhood of Railway Clerks vs. Railway Express Agency.
3114141
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 05, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Prior to 1918 several independent express agencies for delivering freight from the railroad car to the customer existed in the railroad industry. In 1918 several of the independents merged to form the American Railway Express Company, and in 1929 it was purchased by the Class I railroads and renamed Railway Express Agency.
While many of the employees were used jointly as express or railroad employees, and the laws which apply to the rail- road industry were applied to the agency, the vehicular drivers were represented by both the teamsters and the railway clerks. This led to constant friction, each organization trying to secure more for its members than the other.
Following an appeal to the National Mediation Board in 1937, a mediation agreement was signed, giving the teamsters jurisdiction over chauffeurs, helpers and garage men in New York, Newark, Philadelphia, Cleveland, Cincinnati, Chicago, St. Louis and San Francisco The balance of the employees were to be members of the railway clerks,
The Mediation Agreement did not eliminate all the friction. Eighteen emergency boards had been appointed by the president to resolve disputes between the parties prior to the current one,
On January 1. 1955 the teamsters sent a letter to the Agency expressing a desire to revise and modify the rules of the locals operating in New York City. The request was acknowledged and a conference arranged at which the company proposed that the national agreement with the teamsters apply to New York City as well as to the other cities. Several conferences were held, but no agreement was reached. The National Mediation Board took jurisdiction on May 12, but was unable to compose the difference in mediation. The organizations proposed to stop work on July 4, 1955.
The President appointed an emergency board consisting of Robert G. Simmons, Benjamin C. Roberts and Morrison Handsaker under Executive Order 10622 on July 1, 1955. The Board held bearings and submitted its report to the President
on August 1, 1955.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5006: U.S. Emergency Board No. 174 Records 5007: U.S. Emergency Board No. 175 Transcripts and Exhibits 5012: Saul Wallen Papers 5027: U.S. Emergency Board No. 178 Transcripts 5030: U.S. Emergency Board No. 179 Exhibits and Related Material 5036: U.S. Emergency Boards under the Railway Labor Act Reports 5037: U.S. Emergency Board No. 81 Records 5038: U.S. Emergency Board No. 94 Records 5039: U.S. Emergency Board No. 98 Records 5040: U.S. Emergency Board No. 106 Records 5043: U.S. Emergency Board No. 114 Records 5044: U.S. Emergency Board No. 116 Reports and Exhibits 5045: U.S. Emergency Board No. 118 Records 5046: U.S. Emergency Board No. 119 Records 5047: U.S. Emergency Board No. 120 Records 5048: U.S. Emergency Board No. 121 Records 5050: U.S. Emergency Board No. 124 Records 5051: U.S. Emergency Board No. 125 Records 5052: U.S. Emergency Board No. 129 Records 5053: U.S. Emergency Board No. 130 Records 5054: U.S. Emergency Board No. 133 Exhibits 5055: U.S. Emergency Board No. 134 Records 5056: U.S. Emergency Board No. 135 Records 5057: U.S. Emergency Board No. 137 Transcript of Proceedings and Exhibits 5058: U.S. Emergency Board No. 138 Records 5059: U.S. Emergency Board No. 142 Records 5060: U.S. Emergency Board No. 145 Records 5061: U.S. Emergency Board No. 146 Records 5062: U.S. Emergency Board No. 154 Records 5064: U.S. Emergency Board No. 169 Transcript of Proceedings and Exhibits 5075: U.S. Emergency Board under the Taft Hartley Act Records 5579: National Mediation Board Emergency Board 180, Train Crew Consists 5934: Arthur Stark Papers on the President's Emergency Board #219
Arbitration, Industrial--Railroads.; Brotherhood of Railway Clerks.; International Brotherhood of Teamsters.; Railway Express Agency.
3114141
- Transcripts, Exhibits (Company, Union, Board) (Box 1)
  - Transcripts. 12 Volumes, 1411 pages (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Company Exhibit A. Photostatic Copy - Union Demands. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Company Exhibit B. Photostatic Copy - Management's Response Containing Counter Demands (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Company Exhibit C. Wooley Emergency Board Report, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Scope and Contents
    May 23, 1946
  - Company Exhibit D. Report of Cole Emergency Board, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    May 6, 1949
  - Company Exhibit E. Devaney Emergency Report to the President, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    July 10, 1940
  - Company Exhibit F. Stone Emergency Board report, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    November 17, 1941
  - Company Exhibit G. Increases, Decreases, and Adjustments in Express Wage Rates, Brotherhood of Railway Clerks and International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    July 1, 1919-Present (?)
  - Company Exhibit H. Agreement with the Teamsters (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Company Exhibit I. Agreement with the Clerks (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Company Exhibit J. Appendage to Clerks' Agreement (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Company Exhibit K. Morse Board award (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Company Exhibit L. Supplementary report of the Morse Board (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Company Exhibit M. Sharfman Award (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Company Exhibit N. Shaw Board Report (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Company Exhibit O. Calkins Board Report (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Company Exhibit P. Stacy Board Report (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Company Exhibit Q. Swaim Board Report (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Company Exhibit R. Edwards Board Report (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Company Exhibit S. Meyer Board Report (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Company Exhibit T. Lapp Board Report (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Company Exhibit U. Leiserson Board Report (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Company Exhibit V. Lewis Board Report (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Company Exhibit W. Wage Adjustment Order Number 1 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Company Exhibit X. Loring Board Report (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Company Exhibit Y. Mess more Board Report (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Company Exhibit Z. Agreement incorporating the recommendations of the Messmore Board Report, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    March 26, 1954
  - Company Exhibit AA. Map entitled "Routes Between Points" (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Company Exhibit BB. "Proposals for Rule Changes (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Company Exhibit CC. Volume of Traffic Handled on Four Holidays in Relation to Specified Other Days (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Company Exhibit DD. Estimated added cost (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Company Exhibit EE. Vacation schedule (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Company Exhibit FF. Comparison of straight time hourly earnings of all Railway Express Agency and vehicle employees with those of employees in selected industry groups (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Company Exhibit GG. Comparison of average hourly earnings of all Railway Express Agency and vehicle employees (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Company Exhibit HH. Comparison of average weekly earnings of Railway Express employees with those in manufacturing (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Company Exhibit II. Comparison of straight time hourly earnings of Railway Express employees with those in Class I railroads (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Company Exhibit JJ. Comparison of average hourly earnings of Railway Express employees with those of non-operating employees (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Company Exhibit KK. Comparison of average hourly earnings of Railway Express employees with non-operating employees, Class I Railroads (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Company Exhibit LL. Comparison of increases in basic rates of pay of Railway Express rates of pay and those of non-operating employees, 1918-1954 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Company Exhibit MM. Comparison of changes in hourly rates of pay of Railway Express Agency drivers in New York City and those in general trucking industry, 1921- 1954 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Company Exhibit NN. Changes in consumers price index, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    December 1953-January 1955
  - Company Exhibit OO. Comparison of average number of shipments handled per vehicle employee man hour by International Brotherhood of Teamsters employees in 8 cities and all Railway Express Agency vehicle employees, 1946-1954 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Company Exhibit PP. Comparison of productivity of Railway Express Agency vehicle employees represented by the International Brotherhood of Teamsters with the productivity of Class I Railroads (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Company Exhibit QQ. Comparison of productivity of vehicle employees in 8 cities with railroads and with output per man-hour in selected manufacturing industries (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Company Exhibit RR. Indices of production of employees with Railway Express Agency as contrasted with those of Class I Railroads (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Company Exhibit SS. Same comparison as RR in terms of production per man hour (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Company Exhibit TT. Standard Express Operations Agreement (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Company Exhibit UU. "Results of operations for the years 1929 to 1954, inclusive", 1929-1954 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Company Exhibit VV. Reproduction of page 62, Annual Report of Railway Express Agency, Incorporated, to the Interstate Commerce Commission - year ending December 31, 1954. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Company Exhibit WW. Estimated cost of increases as applied to vehicle employees at 8 cities involved for year ended December 31, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Company Exhibit XX. Estimated cost of increases for Railway Express Agency employees excluding thosefor the year ended December 31, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Company Exhibit YY. "Railroad revenues and costs - express traffic" (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Company Exhibit ZZ. Computation of railroad costs incident to express service for Class I Railroads, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Company Exhibit AAA. Record of gross national product beginning with year 1939 and number of express shipments handled each year (Box 1, Folder 54)
    1939- ?
  - Company Exhibit BBB. Graph representing volume of parcel post traffic handled between 1939 and the present (Box 1, Folder 55)
    1939-?
  - Company Exhibit CCC. Estimated intercity ton miles of Class I, II, and III motor trucks volume from 1939 to 1954, 1939-1954 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Company Exhibit DDD. Graph showing growth of air freight from 1945 to 1955, 1945-1955 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Company Exhibit EEE. Graph showing volume of freight forwarder traffic received from shippers between ears 1943 and 1954, 1943-1954 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Company Exhibit FFF. Graph showing volume of freight transportation hauled by line haul railways in period 1939 to 1953, 1939-1953 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Company Exhibit GGG. Graph showing fluctuations in volume of express shipments from 1939 to 1954 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Union Exhibit 1. Freight contract of Local 445, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehouse and Helpers of America (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Union Exhibit 2. Blank copy of contract of paper products and miscellaneous Chauffeurs, Warehousemen and Helpers Local 27 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Union Exhibit 3. Copy of Agreement of Truck Drivers Local Union 807 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Union Exhibit 4. Agreement of Highway and Local Motor Freight Drivers, Dockmen and Helpers, Local Union 707 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Union Exhibit 5. Express and General Trucking Agreement between express Drivers and Chauffeurs and General Trucking Chauffeurs of Local Union 816 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Union Exhibit 6. Teamster Area-wide Negotiating Committee and Local 282, Memorandum of Agreement (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Union Exhibit 7. Contracts in the Coal and Oil Industry, Teamsters Local Union 553, New York (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Union Exhibit 8. Agreement, Truck Drivers Local 282 - Excavating Industry (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Union Exhibit 9. Agreement, Truck Drivers Local 282 - Chauffeurs in the Building Material Industry (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Union Exhibit 10. Agreement, Truck Drivers Local 282 - Lumber Industry (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Union Exhibit 11. Agreement, Truck Drivers Local 282 - Plumbing Industry (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Union Exhibit 12. Agreement, Local Union 816 - Meat Purveyors and Hotel Supply Industry (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Union Exhibit 13. Agreement, Teamsters Local Union 138 - Employers engaged in the handling, distribution, storage of plywood, the plywood industry (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Union Exhibit 14. Agreement, Teamsters Local Union 138 - Employers I the Furniture, Flour, Grocery Teamsters Industry in the City of New York (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Union Exhibit 15. Agreement, Teamsters Local Union 816 - Employers engaged in the Wine and Liquor Industry (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Union Exhibit 16. Agreement - Milk Industry (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Union Exhibit 17. Agreement, Drivers and Chauffeurs Local Union 816 - Meat Market Industry (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Union Exhibit 18. Contract, Armored Car Drivers (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Union Exhibit 19. Agreement, Teamsters - Brewing Industry (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Union Exhibit 101. Letter addressed to Robert C. Hondon, Vice President in Charge of Personnel, giving demands, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    February 4, 1955
  - Union Exhibit 102. "BLS Bulletins 911 for 1946 and 1012 for 1950", 1946-1950 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    1946 and 1950
  - Union Exhibit 103. "Comparison of the Advantage of Earning Power and So on" (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Union Exhibit 104. Cartage Agreement, Chicago Local (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Union Exhibit 105. San Francisco contract (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Union Exhibit 106. "Northern California Teamsters Security Fund" (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Union Exhibit 107. Central States Cartage Agreement (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Union Exhibit 108. "Local Union 100-Covered" (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Union Exhibit 109. "Local Cartage Local Union 100 Cincinnati" (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Union Exhibit 110. Addenda (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Union Exhibit 111. Addenda, Cleveland (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Union Exhibit 112. "Highway Truck Drivers and Helpers Local 107" (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Union Exhibit 113. "Trust Agreement" (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Union Exhibit 114. 1952, Newark. (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Union Exhibit 115. 1954, Newark supplement (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Union Exhibit 116. Pensions (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Union Exhibit 117. Population figures (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Union Exhibit 118. "Schedule of basic hourly wage rates for chauffeurs in selected Saint Louis industry areas since 1942." (Box 1, Folder 97)
    1942-?
  - Union Exhibit 119. Central States Insurance Program - Health and Welfare (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Union Exhibit 120. Teamsters Health and Welfare Plans (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Board Exhibit I. Current Local Agreement - changes Proposed by Organization - Current National Agreement (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Board Exhibit II. Agreement, New York Metropolitan District (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Board Exhibit III. Agreement, National Union Shop, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    March 31, 1952